<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on IGD301 Blog</title>
    <link>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on IGD301 Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture Homework 2: Locomotion Pitch — Gait-Based Arm-Swing for VR Parkour</title>
      <link>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lecture-hw2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lecture-hw2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this homework is straightforward: design a locomotion technique that fits the provided VR parkour scene better than the default. The level is a fixed route with banner timing checkpoints and lots of collectible coins. The key twist is that not all coins are on the ground—some are floating slightly above it. So it’s not just about moving fast. You also need to stop on demand, make small position corrections, and occasionally perform a small vertical action to reach elevated coins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 4 — Roll-a-ball in VR</title>
      <link>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lab4-roll-a-ball-in-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lab4-roll-a-ball-in-vr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Lab 4 focuses on migrating the Lab 3 Roll-a-ball project into a Quest (VR) environment, and implementing two fundamental (and most commonly used) selection techniques: &lt;strong&gt;Direct Selection (near-field grabbing)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Raycasting (far-field ray selection)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
In the end, I built it as a small “tabletop game”: Roll-a-ball is scaled down into a tray/board placed on a table. I can grab the whole board with the controllers, move it around, and drop it. I can also use a right-hand ray to select and grab the board from a distance, while still letting the ball roll inside, collect pickups, and keep the UI readable in VR.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 3 — Roll-a-ball</title>
      <link>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lab3-roll-a-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lab3-roll-a-ball/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Lab 3 follows the Unity Learn Roll-a-ball workflow (Unity 6.3) and delivers a runnable minimal rolling-ball scene: I set up the ground and player sphere in a URP 3D project, configured lighting and materials, and implemented physics-based movement using a Rigidbody together with the new Input System (Player Input).&lt;br&gt;
On top of the tutorial baseline, I added surrounding walls to constrain the play area, and adjusted the camera angle and distance to make the gameplay view more stable and readable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 2 — Setup Unity Environment</title>
      <link>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lab2-setup-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lab2-setup-unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this Lab 2 was to set up a usable Unity development environment and complete a full basic workflow: creating a project, entering the editor, getting familiar with the core panels and operations, and validating the runtime pipeline using Play Mode. This ensures the environment is ready for upcoming course assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-installation&#34;&gt;1. Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed the Unity Editor through Unity Hub and selected Unity 6.3 LTS (6000.3.2f1) on Windows. I chose an LTS release primarily for stability and compatibility, which helps avoid package/plugin issues during iterative course work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 1 — Setup Course Blog</title>
      <link>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lab1-setuo-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lab1-setuo-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this first lab, I set up a public course blog that will host all lecture and lab homeworks for IGD301.&lt;br&gt;
My goals were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a clean, readable blog structure for future posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make local preview easy for fast iteration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy the site online using GitHub Pages so it is always accessible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tooling-choice&#34;&gt;Tooling Choice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;strong&gt;Hugo&lt;/strong&gt; (static site generator) + &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/strong&gt; for hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo is lightweight and fast to build locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown writing is convenient for documenting labs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub Pages + GitHub Actions provides automatic deployment on every push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup-steps&#34;&gt;Setup Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-create-the-hugo-project&#34;&gt;1) Create the Hugo project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a new Hugo site and initialized a git repository:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture Homework 1: Three VR Locomotion Designs </title>
      <link>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lecture-hw1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xyn-1127.github.io/igd301-blog/posts/lecture-hw1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lecture-homework-1-three-vr-locomotion-designs&#34;&gt;Lecture Homework 1: Three VR Locomotion Designs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-a-modern-art-museum-tour&#34;&gt;Scenario: A Modern Art Museum Tour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine visiting a VR recreation of a modern art museum. The exhibition space does not need to be large, but it should create a clear motivation to move around. The task is straightforward: you will visit many exhibits in sequence. In front of each exhibit there is an “optimal viewing spot”, indicated by a subtle circular marker on the floor. Once you step into the marker and stand still, you read or listen to an explanation of about 15 seconds, then move on to the next exhibit, and finally reach the exit to complete the tour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
