<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab on Human-Computer Interaction for Mixed Reality Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/tags/lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lab on Human-Computer Interaction for Mixed Reality Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.155.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/tags/lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lab 5 — Locomotion Technique Implementation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab5-locomotion-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab5-locomotion-technique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post documents the full implementation process of IGD301 Lab Homework 5: taking my locomotion concept from previous assignments and turning it into a working Unity system inside the course-provided parkour scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this lab, all core gameplay locomotion behavior is centralized in &lt;code&gt;LocomotionTechnique.cs&lt;/code&gt;, including movement gating, arm-swing power detection, speed mapping, jump, respawn, stage triggers, and coin collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-goals-and-scene-constraints&#34;&gt;1. Goals and Scene Constraints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This assignment is not a generic locomotion demo. It has to work in the official parkour route, which immediately imposes three constraints:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 4 — Roll-a-ball in VR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab4-roll-a-ball-in-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab4-roll-a-ball-in-vr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Lab 4 focuses on migrating the Lab 3 Roll-a-ball project into a Quest (VR) environment, and implementing two fundamental (and most commonly used) selection techniques: &lt;strong&gt;Direct Selection (near-field grabbing)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Raycasting (far-field ray selection)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
In the end, I built it as a small “tabletop game”: Roll-a-ball is scaled down into a tray/board placed on a table. I can grab the whole board with the controllers, move it around, and drop it. I can also use a right-hand ray to select and grab the board from a distance, while still letting the ball roll inside, collect pickups, and keep the UI readable in VR.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 3 — Roll-a-ball</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab3-roll-a-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab3-roll-a-ball/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Lab 3 follows the Unity Learn Roll-a-ball workflow (Unity 6.3) and delivers a runnable minimal rolling-ball scene: I set up the ground and player sphere in a URP 3D project, configured lighting and materials, and implemented physics-based movement using a Rigidbody together with the new Input System (Player Input).&lt;br&gt;
On top of the tutorial baseline, I added surrounding walls to constrain the play area, and adjusted the camera angle and distance to make the gameplay view more stable and readable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 2 — Setup Unity Environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab2-setup-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab2-setup-unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this Lab 2 was to set up a usable Unity development environment and complete a full basic workflow: creating a project, entering the editor, getting familiar with the core panels and operations, and validating the runtime pipeline using Play Mode. This ensures the environment is ready for upcoming course assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-installation&#34;&gt;1. Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed the Unity Editor through Unity Hub and selected Unity 6.3 LTS (6000.3.2f1) on Windows. I chose an LTS release primarily for stability and compatibility, which helps avoid package/plugin issues during iterative course work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 1 — Setup Course Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab1-setup-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/igd301-blog/posts/lab1-setup-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this first lab, I set up a public course blog that will host all lecture and lab homeworks for this course.&lt;br&gt;
My goals were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a clean, readable blog structure for future posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make local preview easy for fast iteration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy the site online using GitHub Pages so it is always accessible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tooling-choice&#34;&gt;Tooling Choice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;strong&gt;Hugo&lt;/strong&gt;  + &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/strong&gt; for hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo is lightweight and fast to build locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown writing is convenient for documenting labs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub Pages + GitHub Actions provides automatic deployment on every push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup-steps&#34;&gt;Setup Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-create-the-hugo-project&#34;&gt;1) Create the Hugo project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a new Hugo site and initialized a git repository:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
